JENNY KITCHEN

Software Developer

- 615-775-2815
- jennykayekitchen@gmail.com
- LinkedIn
- Github

ABOUT ME

My journey into the field of web development was fueled by a love of design and a desire to use my creativity to build functional and engaging websites that solve real-world problems. I'm excited to use my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React to bring beautiful designs to life that not only meet the needs of my clients but also provide a memorable experience for their users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

CSS

VS Code

SQL

React

Git/Github

C#/.NET

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Nashville Software School in Nashville, Tennessee

November 2022 – Present

Intensive full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. The final half of the program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Source code version control and project management with Git/GitHub
- JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built browser-based single page applications using React, HTML, and CSS
- Styled applications with CSS
- Application design through white boarding dependencies and building ERD's
- Created and modified database design/content using SQL, ADO.NET, and ORM tooling, including exposure and experience with migrations
- Created RESTful APIs with C#/.NET using WebAPI

Technical Projects

My Version / Front-End Capstone

My Version is my front-end capstone project that acts as a playlist generator for Taylor Swift songs. Users can create multiple "moods" and assign one or more moods to each of her songs, and then generate a list of songs based on up to two moods that are selected.

- Tech Utilized: JavaScript, REACT, JSON, HTML, with a focus on CSS and CRUD.
- View Code

Holiday Road / Front-End Group Project

Holiday Road is a group project that allows users to plan a road trip by selecting multiple points of interests including: national parks, attractions, and local eateries. The application provides users with details on each point of interest, weather forecasts, and directions.

- My contributions: All CSS, national parks module
- Tech Utilized: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, public APIs
- View Code

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Learning Coordinator

August 2021 – October 2022

Amazon.com in Nashville, Tennessee

- SME for North American wide, multi-day onboarding program for new external and internal leaders in the field
- Received organization wide recognition for customer service to stakeholders during summer 2022 Town Hall meeting
- Built and maintained internal website to provide stakeholders with an overview of a new leader's onboarding journey from Day 1 through mastery, along with program contact information, metrics, database of announcements, and program pilot information
- Created a weekly mechanism to push program educational material to the field, which was then adopted by a global program to educate other business lines

- Developed and reported out program participation to stakeholders in an effort to resolve attendance issues prior to non-compliance, resulting in 3% reduction of "no shows" for internally promoted leaders
- Developed consistent processes to manage data collection and analysis and reported on key deliverables across multiple business lines and stakeholders
- Collaborated with stakeholders to develop new programs and leveraged existing solutions that helped prepare new leaders for their role and provided immediate business impact
- Built and maintained internal website to provide stakeholders with an overview of a new leader's onboarding journey from Day 1 through mastery, along with program contact information, metrics, database of announcements, and program pilot information
- Worked with multiple lines of businesses to ensure site alignment of business directives
- Recruited and tracked the training progress of SME's that presented both virtual and in-person informational sessions during a new leader's onboarding

DLS Case Manager October 2019 – July 2021

Amazon.com in Nashville, Tennessee

- Built presentations and comprehensive guides to ensure cohesive delivery of material across all training groups
- Coordinated and conducted department wide, small group, and individual trainings sessions based on staff and departmental learning needs, including the creation of training materials for both trainers and learners
- Supported the scheduling, planning, and coordination of training waves
- Developed and tracked survey responses to improve training program
- Coordinated the daily responsibilities of all Launch Pod members to ensure adequate coverage of both training teams and special projects
- Initiated and responded to inquiries about leave and disability events, benefits, and options available to employees
- Served as a point of contact for assigned employees to provide holistic case management services, including reviewing
 medical documentation to adjudicate leaves in compliance with the corresponding leave plans, federal and state laws and
 benefit plans as defined by Amazon
- Responded to employee impacting issues that arose during their LOA and ensured the right communication occurred
- Maintained system records to ensure accurate and timely information/documentation
- Tech Used: DALI, Knet

Total Rewards Analyst

March 2018 - September 2019

CKE Restaurants Holdings, Inc. in Franklin, Tennessee

- Implemented note system within LOA database to ensure all information/communication regarding company leaves of absence were up-to-date and able to be pulled via a report which increased efficiency and accuracy by updating the process from a manual Excel spreadsheet
- Presented benefits overview at new hire orientation and assisted with responding to general benefits questions
- Maintained and updated LOA process guide as processes changed
- Planed events for benefits including the Open Enrollment Fair, Health Fair, onsite flu shots, and EAP sessions
- Maintained appropriate communications with employees on leave including responding to questions in a timely manner, requesting additional paperwork/certifications, extending leaves, and approving returns to work
- Prepared and mailed leave notices, premium payment coupons/delinquent notices, and benefits information
- Evaluated and administered all leave requests across multiple states by designating leave type, determining length of
 eligible time, and eligibility for supplemental benefits
- Ensured employees were paid accurately while on leave by submitting accrued time payouts and validating payroll for all employees on leave
- Managed STD/LTD claims and coordinated benefits with accrued time payouts
- · Tracked incoming premium payments and corrects arrears upon an employee's return to work
- Partnered closely with HRBPs in the field on all related LOAs/claims
- Tracked and processed tuition reimbursement requests
- Tech Used: LeaveSource, HCM Cloud

Branch Administrator Randstad Technologies in Brentwood, Tennessee

March 2016 - March 2018

- Managed onboarding process from start to finish for new hires, to ensure 100% compliance with guidelines
- Audited timecards and invoices on a monthly basis which resulted in revenue savings of over \$10,000 in 2017

- Communicated effectively with recruiters and sales team to ensure all onboarding requirements, including background checks and drug screens, were complete and consultants were ready to report to work on hire date
- Served as a liaison between field operations and the corporate office to quickly and accurately communicate changes in regulations or processes to recruiters, sales team, and the consultants we employed
- Monitored the processing of weekly timecards to ensure proper payment to consultants and invoicing to clients; resolved any over / under payments and delinquencies in the necessary timeframes to avoid lost revenue
- Served as consultants' dedicated contact for all payroll or timekeeping questions concerns, routed all other questions to the appropriate department and followed up to confirm resolution
- Researched and responded promptly to inquiries from other departments
- Maintained all weekly reports, checklists, and documentation
- Provided office support, including: AP, expense reports, gift card purchases through procurement, ordering office supplies and promotional products, filing paperwork, answering main line, routing calls
- Supported management, recruiters, sales team, and other administrators as needed with special projects
- Tech Used: Bullhorn, Workbench

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Nashville Software School in Nashville, Tennessee

November 2022 - Present

Bachelor of Arts in Communication and Information Sciences

The University of Alabama in Tuscaloosa, Alabama

Major: Public Relations • Minor: Computer Applications and Technology

Volunteer Management Certificate

Center for Nonprofit Management in Nashville, Tennessee